<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English blog on 郝鸿涛::Hongtao Hao</title>
    <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English blog on 郝鸿涛::Hongtao Hao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Hugo Themes for a Simple Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/18/good-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:15:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/18/good-themes/</guid>
      <description> lekh  hugo-ink  hugo-universal  ghostwriter  tanka  black and light   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Block CuteStat in a Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/blocking-cutestat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 10:15:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/blocking-cutestat/</guid>
      <description>CuteStat can be really annoying. When I first built my website, and searched my name in Google, mydomain.cutestat.com appeared on top of the resarch restults and it was so ugly!
How can we block CuteStat from crawliing our websites?
A direct way to do this is to go to the bottom of CuteStat , and open Update or Remove .
CuteStat asked us to add a robots.txt file in our website with the following codes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Link in New Tab in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/new-tab-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 09:12:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/new-tab-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The default of Hugo is that when you open a link in a page rendered by markdown, you&amp;rsquo;ll stay in the current tab. How can we enable openning a new tab then?
The answer was provided by PrasdPen .
Go to layouts/_default, create a new folder and name it as _markup. Then add a render-link.html with the following code:
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;{{ .Destination | safeURL }}&amp;#34;{{ with .Title}} title=&amp;#34;{{ . }}&amp;#34;{{ end }}{{ if strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Implement Edit This Page on Github for a Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/18/implement-edit-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:10:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/18/implement-edit-on-github/</guid>
      <description>I saw this quesiton on this thread but the answer by bep did not solve the problem.
The solution can be found in Yihui Xie&amp;rsquo;s book of Blogdown .
However, when I tried the block of codes recommended by Yihui, I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t implement this function of editing on GitHub:
{{ with .File.Path }} &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/.../{{ . }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Edit this page&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; {{ end }} I tried the second block of codes on Yihui&amp;rsquo;s book, and it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Mac Terminal Command Basics</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/14/terminal-command-basics-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 10:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/14/terminal-command-basics-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Changing Folder/File Name If you are too lazy to change the folder or file name manually, you can do that in Terminal. What you need to do is first to go to a the direction the folder/file is located in. For example, if you are changing the name of a folder on your Desktop, then you need to cd Destkop first. Then:
mv oldfoldername newfoldername The same is for when you are changing a file&amp;rsquo;s name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Last Modification Date in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/09/hugo-lastmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:04:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/09/hugo-lastmod/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I thought this must be a difficult undertaking, but later I found this is relatively easy to accomplish.
The solution was here , posted by funkydan2.
According to Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation on Page Variables , there are two ways to specify last modification date. One way is to specify the .Lastmod in a content&amp;rsquo;s front matter. That is to say, while you are specifying the title, date, author, slug, etc., you also specify lastmod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Website Using Hugo without Programming Skills</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/05/get-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 09:26:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/05/get-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>A friend asked me whether I can help him create his own personal website. I have long been wanting to write a simple tutorial on this and now I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to do that.
In this age of informaiton, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have your online presence. It not only helps others to know you more quickly; it also helps you to express yourself to, and share your experiences and knowledge with, the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve the Problem of &#34;Remote Origin Already Exists&#34;</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/25/remote-origin-already-exists-error-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/25/remote-origin-already-exists-error-shooting/</guid>
      <description>Here is my situation: I want to use another GitHub account. I need to transfer a repo from my old account to the new one. Maybe there is an easy way to transfer, but it is beyong my ability now (I guess it&amp;rsquo;s complicated so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother searching for an answer).
So I git clone the repo from my old account and tried to push it to my new accout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Completely Uninstall Homebrew From a Mac</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/23/uninstall-homebrew-completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 15:21:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/23/uninstall-homebrew-completely/</guid>
      <description>My Macbook Air is pretty old1, so I cannot put up with any useless files that take up a lot of space on my laptop.
When installed, Homebrew takes up over 400MB. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of space, at least for me.
I installed Homebrew and then I wanted to delete it. So I went to /usr/local/bin/. I was lost. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t know which files to delete. Since /usr/local/bin/ is a hidden folder in Mac, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mess up with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fix blurry images in Mac Chrome</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/14/chrome-mac-blurry-image-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/14/chrome-mac-blurry-image-fix/</guid>
      <description>I never used Chrome before but after upgrading my MacOS, I started trying Chrome. I created my personal blog using Hugo. The thing is, when I viewed my site using Chrome on my Mac, all images are so blurry. I tried again on Safari, things were fine; I tried it in Chrome on a Windowns PC, things were also fine.
While I was scratching my head, I came across this answer by pastullo on Stackexchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do I Think About TED Talks</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/30/what-do-i-think-about-ted-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:19:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/30/what-do-i-think-about-ted-talks/</guid>
      <description>TED talks say that they have ideas worth spreading, but I am not sure whether these ideas are worth listening.
Many people really like TED talks. These talks were and possibly still are very popular among Chinese students who regard TED talks as a valuable resource to learn English. In this aspect, I agree. TED is very helpful for English learners like me1. After all, most of the speakers are native speakers and their talks are very good for learners to practice listening and speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why so many people love Dr. Fauci</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/19/why-so-many-people-love-dr.-fauci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/19/why-so-many-people-love-dr.-fauci/</guid>
      <description>When I saw the news that there is a petition to name Dr. Anthony Fauci the sexiest man alive, I was puzzled. I have been hearing this name for a long time, since the outbreak of COVID-19 in the United States but have never seen his image and heard of him talking.
Through pure serendipity, I came across this video of Mark Zuckerberg interviewing Dr. Fauci. I was amazed by how calm, confident, and knowledgebale Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What if I don&#39;t have a role model?</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/12/role-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/12/role-model/</guid>
      <description>In elementary school, when asked what I wanted to be when I grew up, just as many other kids, I said I wanted to be a scientist. But many years later when I was graduating from college, I didn’t know where I was heading. There was no longer a great role model guiding my life. I got frightened, especially when many classmates constantly asked me: what do you want to do after graduation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagedown Error Shooting</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/26/pagedown-error-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 11:15:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/26/pagedown-error-shooting/</guid>
      <description>I am now trying to create my curriculum vitae using Pagedown by Yihui Xie . My Mac system is very old: I am still using OS XYosemite (10.10.5). Therefore, I face limitations on the version of R I can use.
Error when downloading Pagedown When downloading pagedown, I tried the method recommended by the Pagedown Homepage , i.e., remotes::install_github(&#39;rstudio/pagedown&#39;) but this does not work for me. There will always be errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab02</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/21/lab02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/21/lab02/</guid>
      <description>W2 Lab: Data processing basics and John Snow&amp;rsquo;s map Follow the contents of this notebook and answer all questions (e.g. Q1: &amp;hellip;)
If you are not familiar with Python yet&amp;hellip; Maybe you can quickly review these basics first.
 numbers and strings ; if and for statement data structure (lists , sets , dictionaries ) functions and modules   Google&amp;rsquo;s Python Class is also a nice resource.
Jupyter + Pandas = Awesomeness Jupyter notebook (lab) (and IPython ) and Pandas may be two most important libraries responsible for the Python&#39;s rise in data science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain-to-brain communication and the Mindnet</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/02/25/b2b-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/02/25/b2b-communication/</guid>
      <description>A conceptual description of how b2b communication works, by Hongtao Hao   Where Does Brain-to-brain Communication Come From? “The Internet of Things” (IoT) captures people’s imagination. Experts envision that things in the future would be interconnected and freely share information with each other. For example, a car, through sensors, would be connected with tunnels and bridges it passes through and all other vehicles. Based on IoT technology and big data, an intelligent transportation system (ITS) could be built which promotes safety, efficiency, and conveniences1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install and Upgrade Hugo on Mac</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/29/how-to-install-and-upgrade-hugo-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 11:05:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/29/how-to-install-and-upgrade-hugo-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>I am only talking about installing and upgrading Hugo on mac in this post. A very important guide is the Hugo&amp;rsquo;s official tutorial on installing Hugo . Homebrew is the easiest way. I did not use this method simply because my MacOS version is so old that I could not install and upgrade Hugo through Homebrew. If you are like me, you can read on.
I chose the second method, which is called &amp;ldquo;Tarball&amp;rdquo; in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s tutorial .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Markdown in Hugo post</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/28/using-markdown-in-hugo-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/28/using-markdown-in-hugo-post/</guid>
      <description>Exercise 4.1 df &amp;lt;- HairEyeColor # Changing the name of HairEyecolor show (df) # displaying the dataframe ## , , Sex = Male ## ## Eye ## Hair Brown Blue Hazel Green ## Black 32 11 10 3 ## Brown 53 50 25 15 ## Red 10 10 7 7 ## Blond 3 30 5 8 ## ## , , Sex = Female ## ## Eye ## Hair Brown Blue Hazel Green ## Black 36 9 5 2 ## Brown 66 34 29 14 ## Red 16 7 7 7 ## Blond 4 64 5 8 e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>