<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English blog on 郝鸿涛::Hongtao Hao</title>
    <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English blog on 郝鸿涛::Hongtao Hao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to a GitHub Project by Creating a New Branch</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/13/git-new-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:34:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/13/git-new-branch/</guid>
      <description>I was invited to an organization account on GitHub. To edit a repository, I thought I could just git clone it, make changes, and then simply git push it. No. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the access.
Then, how to contribute? I first thoguht about Fork. But Isabel Constantino and Professor YY recommended creating a new branch, making changes, and submitting a pull request.
I then wondered: what&amp;rsquo;s the difference between forking and branch?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Different Fonts on Overleaf</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/13/overleaf-latex-fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 10:07:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/13/overleaf-latex-fonts/</guid>
      <description>Two steps Using different fonts is much easier than I thought. It involves two steps:
  Change the Compiler from LaTex or pdfLatex to either XeLaTex or LuaLaTex. To make this change, click the Menu button on the upper-left corner of your Overleaf project. In Settings, you&amp;rsquo;ll see a drop list in Compiler.
  Add these two lines:
  \usepackage{fontspec} \setmainfont{Choose Your Own Font} Where to find the fonts that were supported via fontspec?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Shortcode Links in a New Tab in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/11/new-tab-in-shortcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 22:23:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/11/new-tab-in-shortcode/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about how to open links in new tab in Hugo here . But how can we open links in new tab in a Hugo shortcode, for example, Hugo&amp;rsquo;s built-in shortcode for figure ?
I found the solution here . Thanks to ju52&amp;rsquo;s answer.
First, copy the original codes of the figure shortcode. Paste them in a new html file named figure.html. Place this file in layouts/shortcodes. Create a folder named shortcodes within the layouts folder if you don&amp;rsquo;t have it yet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Shortcodes in Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/shortcode-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 16:59:52 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/shortcode-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>I found the way to use shortcodes in Blogdown here .
Take the shortcodes of my custom block as an example. If I want to use them in a post created by Blogdown , I&amp;rsquo;ll do it this way:
`r blogdown:shortcode(&amp;quot;block&amp;quot;, class=&amp;quot;note&amp;quot;)` Write my note information here. `r blogdown:shortcode(&amp;quot;end&amp;quot;)` The above codes will create this:
Write my note information here. 
Thanks, Yihui !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Custom Blocks in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/custom-blocks-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:58:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/custom-blocks-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I thought creating custom blocks in Hugo would be difficult. But with Hugo&amp;rsquo;s shortcodes, and the CSS from Yihui Xie&amp;rsquo;s Bookdown project, it can be super easy.
Download images and edit stylesheet First of all, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to download five images from here : caution, important, note, tip, and warning.png. Add these images to the static folder of your Hugo project. I suppose you are adding them to the root directory of static.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Delete and Ignore All .DS_Store Files in GitHub Repositories</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/delete-ignore-ds-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 15:01:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/03/delete-ignore-ds-store/</guid>
      <description>If you are using a Mac, chances are that you have a lot of .DS_Store files in all kinds of folders. While they don&amp;rsquo;t cause any problems, it might be ugly if these files appear in your GitHub repositories. How to delete and ignore all of them? This thread on Stack Overflow helped me quite a bit.
First, delete all .DS_Store files The following solution came from here .
At the root of your local repository1, run:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tell Hugo Not to Parse HTML</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/avoid-parsing-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 16:09:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/avoid-parsing-html/</guid>
      <description>I found the solution here by Hissatsu . You can use encode convert XML to US-ASCII.
For example:
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;I do not want to show this content.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
If you encode multiple lines of code, you&amp;rsquo;ll find that the output will become only one line. You solve the problem by adding &amp;lt;/br&amp;gt; at the end of each line except the last line.
For example, if I want the output to be this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Display Full Width Images in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/full-width-image-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 15:13:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/full-width-image-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I originally thought it must be super difficult to have full width images in a Hugo post because the width of my body text is already defined and yet all figures have to be within body. I stumbled upon a very easy solution here .
Add the following1 to your website stylesheet:
.fullwidth { width: 100vw; position: relative; left: 50%; right: 50%; margin-left: -50vw; margin-right: -50vw; } Then, when using Hugo&amp;rsquo;s built-in figure shortcode , include class=&amp;quot;fullwidth&amp;quot; :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Embed an Observable Notebook in A Hugo Blog</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/observable-hugo-embed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 11:38:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/observable-hugo-embed/</guid>
      <description>Embedding an Observable notebook in a Hugo blog post is no different than embedding it in a stand alone webpage . Also, you can read this tutorial on Observable Jekyll . Although it used Jekyll as an example, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly the same for Hugo.
Direct embedding through iframe You can embed a visualization on ObservableHQ directly through an iframe. I talked it about how to do it here .
This is the result:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Embed An Observable Notebook in A Stand-alone Webpage</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/exporting-observable-notebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 09:03:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/11/02/exporting-observable-notebook/</guid>
      <description>After designing data visualizations on ObserbableHQ , you might want to present your them in a stand-alone webpage. This post is to teach you how to do it.
If you find my post not helpful, you can refer to Advanced Embedding and Downloading .
Embed directly via iframe It&amp;rsquo;s relatively easy to embed a visualization directly . For this example of mine, to embed this chart , I just need the following codes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My thoughts on &#34;Science in the age of selfies&#34;</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/17/science-selfies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 17:08:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/17/science-selfies/</guid>
      <description>I encountered this opinion article, Science in the age of selfies , published on PNAS when I searched &amp;ldquo;selfies&amp;rdquo; on Google Scholar. I thought it was about selfies, but it was not at all.
Although not about a topic I thought it was, this opinion is very well written and has some insightful ideas, at least for me. I will in the following talk about what I thought about several major arguments in this article and what I learned from them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Understand the Difference Between If Statements and While Loops</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/13/if-while/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 16:20:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/13/if-while/</guid>
      <description>For beginners, whichever programming language you are learning, it might be difficult to differentiate the difference between if statements and while loop. In this blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ll take Python and Javascript as examples to illustrate the differences between the two.
Both statements are made up of two parts:
 Condition statement; and Conditional code.  Conditional code will be execuated only if the condition statements are true.
Okay, those are the similaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Download Wget for Mac without Homebrew</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/07/wget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 11:53:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/07/wget/</guid>
      <description>There are four ways to download Wget :
 Via Xcode .  However, Xcode takes up more than 10 GB when installed. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s worth it to download Xcode simply for Wget.
Official website of Gun  I tried to download wget2-1.99.2.tar.gz from https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/wget/ which I got from https://www.gnu.org/software/wget/ .
cd ~/Downloads curl -O https://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/wget/wget2-1.99.2.tar.gz tar -zxvf wget2-1.99.2.tar.gz cd wget2-1.99.2/ ./configure make make install wget http://ftp.gnu.org/gnu/wget/wget-1.19.5.tar.gz However, errors occured.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Make a Pull Request on GitHub</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/github-pull-request/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 16:56:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/github-pull-request/</guid>
      <description>I learned how to contribute via making a pull request from the contributing guidance by Victorial Drake .
Step1: Fork a repo Reference: Fork a repo from GitHub Docs Forking the original repository Simply fork the project you would like to work on. For example, I forked Professor YY&amp;rsquo;s covid19-data . Here is what the fork looks like.
Making a local clone of your fork In Terminal, first navigate to the directory where you want to place this local clone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Links to Headings in A Hugo Post</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/hugo-heading-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 15:07:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/hugo-heading-link/</guid>
      <description>I tried the render hooks for headings , a new feature released in Hugo 0.71. However, it didn&amp;rsquo;t work for me.
I then go back to the solution suggested by frerich . It worked.
I changed the &amp;amp;para; to #.
According to frerich, what you need to do is to add add-header-anchors.html whose content is shown below to /layouts/partials.
{{ . | replaceRE &amp;quot;(&amp;lt;h[1-9] id=\&amp;quot;([^\&amp;quot;]+)\&amp;quot;.+)(&amp;lt;/h[1-9]+&amp;gt;)&amp;quot; ${1}¶${3} | safeHTML }}
Then, in /layouts/_default/single.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is sys.argv in Python and How to Use It</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/python-sys-argv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 11:58:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/10/05/python-sys-argv/</guid>
      <description>While I was updating the data for Professor YY &amp;lsquo;s COVID19-data project , I noticed some lines of codes containing sys.argv. I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand it in the begining, nor was I sure how to use it. I understood it later. This post is to explain what sys.argv is and how to use it.
Python sys.argv is essentially a variable from the sys module. This variable contains arguments that are to be passed to the python script you are calling in the command line1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting for Using the Hugo Sam Theme</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/19/hugo-sam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 09:59:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/19/hugo-sam/</guid>
      <description>There are several things you need to prepare to preview locally and deploy a Hugo site which uses the Sam theme .
Install Node.js, npm, postcss-cli, and autoprefixer Victoria recommends installing Node.js and npm this way . However, after the installation, when running npm install -g postcss-cli and npm install -g autoprefixer to install postcss-cli and autoprefixer, a permission error might occur:
Error: EACCES: permission denied, access &amp;#39;/usr/local/lib/node_modules&amp;#39; This thread documented this problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Understand D3.js Continuous Scales</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/07/d3-scales/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/07/d3-scales/</guid>
      <description>Why Bother Using D3 Scales? Couldn’t We Plot It Directly? What are Input Domain and Output Range? How do the input domain and output range work? D3 Scales Do Not Capture Relative Length How does d3.scaleLinear() work? What Does d3.scaleLinear() Preserve? How to Maintain Relative Length? Closing Words Other resourses   Most online tutorials on D3 scales, at best do not get the point, and at worst are really misleading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Have Learned from Professor YY</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/05/yy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 13:54:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/09/05/yy/</guid>
      <description>The following only applies to social sciences. I know nothing about natural sciences communities. 
I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much from Professor Yong-Yeon (&amp;ldquo;YY&amp;rdquo;) Ahn . Aside from knowledge and skills1, I learned how to get along with (my future) students, find a job after a PhD, and be a good scholar and a good person.
I thought about writing this blog after the Zoom meeting yesterday where he shared his experience about finding a job after PhD or a post-doc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Print Directory Trees on Mac</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/31/mac-directory-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 10:55:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/31/mac-directory-tree/</guid>
      <description>I tried to simply the process as the original solution is still a little bit cumbersom.
You can view the source codes of the GitHub Repository here .
What you need to do is to first open a new Terminal, and
cd Desktop # Navigate to Desktop where we&amp;#39;ll be downloading the repo git clone https://github.com/hongtaoh/tree-1.8.0 # Clone the repo mv ~/Desktop/tree-1.8.0/tree /usr/local/bin/ # Move tree to /usr/local/bin Done.
You can generate the directory tree under the current directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continous Local Preview in Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/24/blogdown-continous-local-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 17:03:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/24/blogdown-continous-local-preview/</guid>
      <description>Yihui talked about local preview in Blogdown here and here , but they were not very straightforward.
How to do it then?
Basically, you only need to Serve Site once. In the drop list of Addins, choose Serve Site. Later, when you make changes in your .Rmd files, you just need to save the changes by Command + S (in Mac) or clicking the Save button in Rstudio. These changes will be updated automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read Local or Online Files in Rmarkdown, Bookdown, and Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/24/reading-online-and-local-files-in-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/24/reading-online-and-local-files-in-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Reading Online Files Reading Local Files Files in a different directory Files in a the same directory Relative path WITHOUT using here Relative path using here     Here is a tutorial on how to read local data files in Rmarkdown. I found it very helpful. Nonetheless, I decided to write on this topic again myself because that post is a bit more complicated than it should be.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to read graphs using igraph in R</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/21/reading-gml-file-using-igraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/21/reading-gml-file-using-igraph/</guid>
      <description>You can read the official documentation on read_graph() here for more info. Be sure to put the file name in between quotation marks. For example:
library(igraph) read_graph(&amp;quot;lesmiss.gml&amp;quot;, format = &amp;quot;gml&amp;quot;) For more information on how to read local files, refer to this post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Include fig.cap when referencing a figure in Bookdown or Blogdown</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/21/including-fig-cap-when-referencing-a-figure-in-bookdown-or-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/21/including-fig-cap-when-referencing-a-figure-in-bookdown-or-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Yihui documented figure referencing very well. There is only one thing I need to add: do remember to add a figure caption if you want to reference it.
For example, if we have a chunk label without a figure caption:
plot(pressure) We cannot reference it: Figure ??.
This is because without a figure caption, the figure won’t be numbered. Without a number, the figure cannot be referenced.
Simply adding a figure caption solves the problem:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plot a Network&#39;s Degree Distribution Using igraph in R</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/19/plot-degree-distribution-using-igraph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/19/plot-degree-distribution-using-igraph/</guid>
      <description>Getting a deeper understanding of degree() and degree_distribution() Plotting the distribution Going back to histogram Deciding on X-axis scale Adjusting a histogram’s breaks Adjusting a histogram’s Y-axis  Conclusion How to draw a bar chart to display a network’s degree distribution How to draw a histogram to display a network’s nodes degrees  Another option   The R package igraph is very useful. However, its degree() and degree_distribution() function is not so straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Shipping Scam</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/17/amazon-shipping-scam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 15:08:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/17/amazon-shipping-scam/</guid>
      <description>After clicking &amp;ldquo;Buy Now&amp;rdquo;, you&amp;rsquo;ll see in &amp;ldquo;Total&amp;rdquo; that the price is much higher than it should be. This is because Amazon chooses the default shipping method which charges around $8 even though the stuff you are purchasing should include free shipping.
What should we do then?
Click the first row which says &amp;ldquo;Arriving &amp;hellip;&amp;quot;, and from there, choose &amp;ldquo;FREE Shipping&amp;rdquo;.
Lesson learned: Never be deceiful as Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Set up A Custom Subdomain For Netlify</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/10/netlify-subdomain-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 14:45:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/10/netlify-subdomain-setup/</guid>
      <description>To configure a custom subdomain for Netlify (for example, to point legacy-jupyterbook.hongtaoh.com to legacy-jupyterbook.netlify.app) should be very easy, but the instructions on Netlify can be a little confusing, even misleading.
  The confusing instruction   The most confusing point is shown above. It asks you to add a custom domain in the format of www.yourdomain.com. However, that is for configuring a custom domain, not a custom subdomain. Then, what should you do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update Pandoc for Rmarkdown And Bookdown</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/09/updating-pandoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 09:54:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/08/09/updating-pandoc/</guid>
      <description>Rmarkdown and Bookdown are highly reliant on Pandoc. Sometimes, issues may happen when Rstudio is using an older version of Pandoc even if you have downloaded the newest version, as was discussed here .
Yihui&amp;rsquo;s Solution Yihui provided a solution : to put the newest version of pandoc into /usr/local/bin. How to do it?
First of all, you need to install the updated version of Pandoc you want. Remember the path where it is installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Legacy Jupyterbook</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/25/legacy-jupyterbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 16:13:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/25/legacy-jupyterbook/</guid>
      <description>About Jupyterbook Jupyterbook totally changed the way a book is built in April 2020. The final legacy version is v0.6.5 . You can compare the legacy demo with the newest version demo .
You can install the legacy version here .
Using Jupyterbook In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly talk about how to use this legacy version of jupyterbook together with GitHub and Netlify.
First off, you should install the legacy version using pip install jupyter-book==0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Hugo Themes for a Simple Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/18/good-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:15:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/07/18/good-themes/</guid>
      <description> lekh  hugo-ink  hugo-universal  ghostwriter  tanka  black and light  Archive  Devise  Diary  Sam  Cleanwhite  Basic Web Theme  etch  Hyde  Hugo Frais   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Block CuteStat in a Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/blocking-cutestat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 10:15:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/blocking-cutestat/</guid>
      <description>CuteStat can be really annoying. When I first built my website, and searched my name in Google, mydomain.cutestat.com appeared on top of the resarch restults and it was so ugly!
How can we block CuteStat from crawliing our websites?
A direct way to do this is to go to the bottom of CuteStat , and open Update or Remove .
CuteStat asked us to add a robots.txt file in our website with the following codes:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Open Links in New Tab in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/new-tab-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 09:12:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/20/new-tab-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The default of Hugo is that when you open a link in a page rendered by markdown, you&amp;rsquo;ll stay in the current tab. How can we enable openning a new tab then?
The answer was provided by PrasdPen .
Go to layouts/_default, create a new folder and name it as _markup. Then add a render-link.html with the following code:
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;#34;{{ .Destination | safeURL }}&amp;#34;{{ with .Title}} title=&amp;#34;{{ . }}&amp;#34;{{ end }}{{ if strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Implement Edit This Page on Github for a Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/18/implement-edit-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 11:10:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/18/implement-edit-on-github/</guid>
      <description>I saw this quesiton on this thread but the answer by bep did not solve the problem.
The solution can be found in Yihui Xie&amp;rsquo;s book of Blogdown .
However, when I tried the block of codes recommended by Yihui, I still couldn&amp;rsquo;t implement this function of editing on GitHub:
{{ with .File.Path }} &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/.../{{ . }}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Edit this page&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; {{ end }} I tried the second block of codes on Yihui&amp;rsquo;s book, and it works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Mac Terminal Command Basics</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/14/terminal-command-basics-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 10:04:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/14/terminal-command-basics-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>Changing Folder/File Name If you are too lazy to change the folder or file name manually, you can do that in Terminal. What you need to do is first to go to a the direction the folder/file is located in. For example, if you are changing the name of a folder on your Desktop, then you need to cd Destkop first. Then:
mv oldfoldername newfoldername The same is for when you are changing a file&amp;rsquo;s name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Last Modification Date in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/09/hugo-lastmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 12:04:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/09/hugo-lastmod/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I thought this must be a difficult undertaking, but later I found this is relatively easy to accomplish.
The solution was here , posted by funkydan2.
According to Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation on Page Variables , there are two ways to specify last modification date. One way is to specify the .Lastmod in a content&amp;rsquo;s front matter. That is to say, while you are specifying the title, date, author, slug, etc., you also specify lastmod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Website Using Hugo without Programming Skills</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/05/get-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 09:26:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/06/05/get-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>A friend asked me whether I can help him create his own personal website. I have long been wanting to write a simple tutorial on this and now I think it&amp;rsquo;s time to do that.
In this age of informaiton, it&amp;rsquo;s important to have your online presence. It not only helps others to know you more quickly; it also helps you to express yourself to, and share your experiences and knowledge with, the outside world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Solve the Problem of &#34;Remote Origin Already Exists&#34;</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/25/remote-origin-already-exists-error-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 10:10:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/25/remote-origin-already-exists-error-shooting/</guid>
      <description>Here is my situation: I want to use another GitHub account. I need to transfer a repo from my old account to the new one. Maybe there is an easy way to transfer, but it is beyong my ability now (I guess it&amp;rsquo;s complicated so I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother searching for an answer).
So I git clone the repo from my old account and tried to push it to my new account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Completely Uninstall Homebrew From a Mac</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/23/uninstall-homebrew-completely/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 15:21:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/23/uninstall-homebrew-completely/</guid>
      <description>My Macbook Air is pretty old1, so I cannot put up with any useless files that take up a lot of space on my laptop.
When installed, Homebrew takes up over 400MB. That&amp;rsquo;s a lot of space, at least for me.
I installed Homebrew and then I wanted to delete it. So I went to /usr/local/bin/. I was lost. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t know which files to delete. Since /usr/local/bin/ is a hidden folder in Mac, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mess up with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Blurry Images in Mac Chrome</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/14/chrome-mac-blurry-image-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:35:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/05/14/chrome-mac-blurry-image-fix/</guid>
      <description>I never used Chrome before but after upgrading my MacOS, I started trying Chrome. I created my personal blog using Hugo. The thing is, when I viewed my site using Chrome on my Mac, all images are so blurry. I tried again on Safari, things were fine; I tried it in Chrome on a Windowns PC, things were also fine.
While I was scratching my head, I came across this answer by pastullo on Stackexchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do I Think About TED Talks</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/30/what-do-i-think-about-ted-talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 06:19:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/30/what-do-i-think-about-ted-talks/</guid>
      <description>TED talks say that they have ideas worth spreading, but I am not sure whether those ideas are worth listening.
Many people really like TED talks. These talks were and possibly still are very popular among Chinese students who regard TED talks as a valuable resource to learn English. In this aspect, I agree. TED is very helpful for English learners like me1. After all, most of the speakers are native speakers and their talks are very good for learners to practice listening and speaking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Do So Many People Love Dr. Fauci</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/19/why-do-so-many-people-love-dr.-fauci/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/19/why-do-so-many-people-love-dr.-fauci/</guid>
      <description>When I saw the news that there is a petition to name Dr. Anthony Fauci the sexiest man alive, I was puzzled. I have been hearing this name for a long time since the outbreak of COVID-19 in the United States, but have never seen his image and heard of him talking.
Through pure serendipity, I came across this video of Mark Zuckerberg interviewing Dr. Fauci. I was amazed by how calm, confident, and knowledgebale Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What If I Don&#39;t Have A Role Model?</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/12/role-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/04/12/role-model/</guid>
      <description>In elementary school, when asked what I wanted to be when I grew up, just as many other kids, I said I wanted to be a scientist. But many years later when I was graduating from college, I didn’t know where I was heading. There was no longer a great role model guiding my life. I got frightened, especially when many classmates constantly asked me: what do you want to do after graduation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagedown Error Shooting</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/26/pagedown-error-shooting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 11:15:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/03/26/pagedown-error-shooting/</guid>
      <description>I am now trying to create my curriculum vitae using Pagedown by Yihui Xie . My Mac system is very old: I am still using OS XYosemite (10.10.5). Therefore, I face limitations on the version of R I can use.
Error when downloading Pagedown When downloading pagedown, I tried the method recommended by the Pagedown Homepage , i.e., remotes::install_github(&#39;rstudio/pagedown&#39;) but this does not work for me. There will always be errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain-to-brain communication and the Mindnet</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/02/25/b2b-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/02/25/b2b-communication/</guid>
      <description>A conceptual description of how b2b communication works, by Hongtao Hao   Where Does Brain-to-brain Communication Come From? “The Internet of Things” (IoT) captures people’s imagination. Experts envision that things in the future would be interconnected and freely share information with each other. For example, a car, through sensors, would be connected with tunnels and bridges it passes through and all other vehicles. Based on IoT technology and big data, an intelligent transportation system (ITS) could be built which promotes safety, efficiency, and conveniences1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install and Upgrade Hugo on Mac</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/29/how-to-install-and-upgrade-hugo-on-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 11:05:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/29/how-to-install-and-upgrade-hugo-on-mac/</guid>
      <description>I am only talking about installing and upgrading Hugo on mac in this post. A very important guide is the Hugo&amp;rsquo;s official tutorial on installing Hugo . Homebrew is the easiest way. I did not use this method simply because my MacOS version is so old that I could not install and upgrade Hugo through Homebrew. If you are like me, you can read on.
I chose the second method, which is called &amp;ldquo;Tarball&amp;rdquo; in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s tutorial .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Rmarkdown in Hugo post</title>
      <link>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/28/using-markdown-in-hugo-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hongtaoh.github.io/en/2020/01/28/using-markdown-in-hugo-post/</guid>
      <description>Exercise 4.1 df &amp;lt;- HairEyeColor # Changing the name of HairEyecolor show (df) # displaying the dataframe ## , , Sex = Male ## ## Eye ## Hair Brown Blue Hazel Green ## Black 32 11 10 3 ## Brown 53 50 25 15 ## Red 10 10 7 7 ## Blond 3 30 5 8 ## ## , , Sex = Female ## ## Eye ## Hair Brown Blue Hazel Green ## Black 36 9 5 2 ## Brown 66 34 29 14 ## Red 16 7 7 7 ## Blond 4 64 5 8 e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>